

johnthrapp@gmail.com

Indianapolis, IN

Profile

Ambitious young professional with a recently-found passion for coding. Previously studied Business at the Kelley School at IU and worked in Technology Sales. Excited to connect with Indy employers and play a more technical role with a dev team.

Employment History

Inside Account Executive, SHI International (Austin, TX)

February 2018 — July 2019

- As a technology reseller, helped customers implement a variety of solutions
- Oversaw the entire sales cycle, from prospecting to placing orders
- Developed a book of 30-50 SMB organizations in the Pacific-NW region
- Personally booked & conducted over 120 formal customer calls (prescheduled demos or roadmaps including a product specialist)
- Generated over \$850,000 in revenue and over \$100,000 in gross margin

Business Development Intern, Perscio (Carmel, IN)

May 2017 — August 2017

- Managed an email campaign for Perscio, a technology startup in its early stages
- Met with the president weekly to present data, evaluate effectiveness
- Wrote a detailed outline of the processes and made suggestions to improve

Account Associate, Bloomerang (Indianapolis, IN)

March 2020 — April 2020

- Experienced a startup environment with a successful web app product
- Learned a significant amount about non-profits and their CRM needs
- Furthered an interest in coding by speaking with product team

Education

B.S. in Business, Indiana University Kelley School (Bloomington, IN)

August 2013 — December 2017

• Majors: Marketing & Professional Sales

Minor: Psychology

Web Development, Eleven Fifty Academy (Fishers, IN)

June 2020 — September 2020

- Completed several projects (links for each in portfolio):
 - Full-stack Grocery App (P.E.R.N. stack team project)
 - Full-stack Note App (P.E.R.N. stack individual)
 - CSS Creature
 - Static Netflix Page
 - Random Pokemon Generator (using external API)
- Learned version control using Github and deployment using Heroku
- Solidified a passion for coding and overcoming challenges both individually and while collaborating with a team

Details

Indianapolis, IN johnthrapp@gmail.com

Links

Github

Portfolio

LinkedIn

Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Bootstrap

React - Legacy/Class

Components

React - Hooks

ReactStrap (and other

component libraries)

Node.js

Express.js

PostgreSQL

GitHub

Heroku

Account Management

Sales Prospecting Tools

CRM Systems

Order Fulfillment Systems

Fluent in Spanish

Graphic Design

Adobe Creative Suite

Microsoft Office

Hobbies

Audiobooks, Music, Video Games, Tennis, Hiking, Biking, Watching Colts/Pacers